var myFlashcards = [     {question:"test of obviousness whether prior art teachings taken as a whole would have made obvious",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/07/steele-gorman-process-control-raytheon.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>gorman</b></span> </a>'},{question:"position label's function given no patentable weight because a distinction discernable only to the human mind",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/07/gulack-bernhart-lowry-xiao.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>gulack, bernhart, lowry, xiao</b></span></a>'},{question:"reasonable expectation of success needs sufficient predictability in the art",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/07/droge-kubin-ofarrell.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>droge, kubin, ofarrell</b></span></a>'},{question:"mere duplication of parts inapplicable when unexpected result",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/07/harza.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>harza</b></span></a>'},{question:"admitted prior art can be used for both anticipation and obviousness",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/08/riverwood.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>riverwood</b></span></a>'},{question:"derivation shown by establishing prior conception and communication to another",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/08/brand.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>brand</b></span></a>'},{question:"using patent in suit as guide through maze of prior art references is hindsight reconstruction",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/08/ntp.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>NTP</b></span></a>'},{question:"specific finding on level of skill not required when prior art reflects it",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/08/litton.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>Litton</b></span></a>'},{question:"obviousness is legal conclusion",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/08/apple.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>apple</b></span></a>'},{question:"no patentable combination between a device and the material upon which it works",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/08/otto-young-rishoi-mcgrew.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>otto, young, rishoi</b></span></a>'},{question:"where there are differences between reference disclosure and claim, rejection must be based on 103 not 102",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/09/titanium.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>titanium</b></span></a>'},{question:"to teach away reference must discourage POSITA from following path or lead in a divergent direction",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/09/gurley.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>gurley</b></span></a>'},{question:"POSITA needs a reason",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/09/takeda.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>takeda</b></span></a>'},{question:"examiner's mere speculation not sufficient for prima facie case of obviousness",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/09/warner-sporck.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>warner, sporck</b></span></a>'},{question:"economics may motivate POSITA to choose least expensive alternative",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/09/clinton.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>Clinton</b></span></a>'},{question:"even after KSR examiner must still discuss reason a particular feature would have been obvious",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/09/vaidyanathan.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>vaidyanathan</b></span></a>'},{question:"needs mere reversal of working parts to not constitute invention not more",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/10/einstein.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>Einstein</b></span></a>'},{question:"unexpected 'synergistic' properties, must be an effect greater than the sum of the several effects taken separately.",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/10/merck-sakraida.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>merck, sakraida</b></span></a>'},{question:"mere existence of differences not enough to establish non-obviousness",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/10/dann.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>dann</b></span></a>'},{question:"automating a manual activity is not invention",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/10/venner-leapfrog.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>venner, leapfrog</b></span></a>'},{question:"103 combination can't change basic principles under which primary reference operates",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/10/ratti.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>ratti</b></span></a>'},{question:"change in the basic principles of operation means scientific or technical principles under which invention operates",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/10/ratti_21.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>ratti</b></span></a>'},{question:"103 must rest on factual basis",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/10/warner.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>warner</b></span></a>'},{question:"103 suggestion test requires consideration of common knowledge and common sense",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/11/dystar.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>dystar</b></span></a>'},{question:"102 prior art also available under 103, even applicant's own patented work",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/11/andresen.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>Andresen</b></span></a>'},{question:"order of performing steps must produce new and unexpected result to overcome 103",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/11/hampel-burhans.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>hampel, burhans</b></span></a>'},{question:"merely establishing two prior arts different not enough for 'teaching away' from combination",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/11/depuy-spine-fulton-beattie.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>beattie</b></span></a>'},{question:"to teach away prior art must 'criticize, discredit, or otherwise discourage' investigation",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/11/depuy-spine-fulton-beattie.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>depuy spine, fulton</b></span></a>'},{question:"obvious only if POSITA can discover workable ranges by routine experimentation",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/11/aller.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>aller</b></span></a>'},{question:"proper to take into account inferences POSITA reasonably expected to draw from prior art",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/11/preda.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>preda</b></span></a>'},{question:"claiming new benefit of old process not patentable",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/11/woodruff-perricone-bristol-myers.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>woodruff, perricone, bristol-myers</b></span></a>'},{question:"test for obviousness is what combined teachings of references would have suggested to POSITA",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/11/keller.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>keller</b></span></a>'},{question:"arguing about the age of references useless absent evidence the art tried and failed to solve the problem",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/12/wright.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>wright</b></span></a>'},{question:"determination of optimum values prima facie obvious but optimum values outside suggested range may not be obvious",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/12/sebek.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>sebek</b></span></a>'},{question:"express suggestion to substitute one known equivalent for another not necessary to be obvious",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/12/fout-mayne.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>fout, mayne</b></span></a>'},{question:"in 103 examiner may not resort to speculation, unfounded assumptions, or hindsight reconstruction",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/12/warner.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>warner</b></span></a>'},{question:"precedent cannot establish facts",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/12/einstein-case.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>case</b></span></a>'},{question:"mere reversal of essential working parts routine",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/12/einstein-case.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>einstein</b></span></a>'},{question:"little better evidence negating expectation of success than actual reports of failure",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/12/cyclobenzaprine-boehringer.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>cyclobenzaprine, boehringer</b></span></a>'},{question:"court can't use appellant's disclosure as a blueprint to reconstruct invention from prior art",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/12/warner-grain-processing.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>grain processing</b></span></a>'},{question:"examiner may not resort to speculation, unfounded assumption or hindsight reconstruction",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/12/warner-grain-processing.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>warner</b></span></a>'},{question:"if examiner establishes knowledge in the art burden on applicant to traverse to create reasonable doubt",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2013/12/boon-bozek.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>boon, bozek</b></span></a>'},{question:"POSITA can pursue finite number of identified, predictable solutions to solve design need",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/01/ksr.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>ksr</b></span></a>'},{question:"Arguments and conclusions unsupported by factual evidence carry no evidentiary weight",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/01/de-blauwe.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>de blauwe</b></span></a>'},{question:"examiner must make prima facie case, burden shifts, appellant comes forward with evidence/argument",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/01/sullivan-glaug.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>sullivan, glaug</b></span></a>'},{question:"claim unpatentable if so broad it also reads on obvious subject matter",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/02/lintner.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>lintner</b></span></a>'},{question:"for known or used in this country means accessible to public, not for TSM (after KSR)",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/02/carella-dailey-ksr.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>carella</b></span></a>'},{question:"change in shape or form may be within skill of POSITA",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/02/carella-dailey-ksr.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>dailey</b></span></a>'},{question:"does examiner provide reason with rationale underpinning for proposed combination?",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/02/carella-dailey-ksr.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>KSR</b></span></a>'},{question:"when secondary considerations are present, error not to consider them",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/02/kao-soni.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>kao, soni</b></span></a>'},{question:"103 combination requires more than hindsight gleaned from invention itself",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/02/interconnect.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>interconnect</b></span></a>'},{question:"artisan must be presumed to know something apart from what references disclose",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/02/allen-engg-bell-comm-jacoby.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>jacoby</b></span></a>'},{question:"exception to 'aller' rule, optimization of a parameter not recognized as being result-effective not obvious",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/02/antonie.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>antonie</b></span></a>'},{question:"obvious if POSITA, before and without knowledge, would have found it easily predictable and achievable variation of prior art",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/02/rolls-royce.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>rolls-royce</b></span></a>'},{question:"unexpected results must be commensurate in scope with protection sought by claim",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/03/harris.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>harris</b></span></a>'},{question:"1) general conditions of claim must be disclosed in prior art 2) discovery of range routine",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/03/aller.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>aller</b></span></a>'},{question:"routine experimentation to find optimum concentration of components of known compound obvious",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/03/boesch.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>boesch</b></span></a>'},{question:"entitled to a patent where no prima facie case of obviousness",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/03/rouffet.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>rouffet</b></span></a>'},{question:"optimal values outside of a recognized range may be not obvious",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/03/sebek.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>sebek</b></span></a>'},{question:"must show particular range critical, generally by showing unexpected results relative to prior art range",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/03/woodruff.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>woodruff</b></span></a>'},{question:"103 rejection when a second reference identifies the benefits of adding a feature to the primary reference",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/03/self-thrift.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>thrift</b></span></a>'},{question:"POSITA obvious to try: 'good reason to pursue the known options within his or her technical grasp.'",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2015/03/warner-takeda.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>warner, takeda</b></span></a>'},{question:"number of units sold provides a very weak showing of commercial success",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/03/huang-cable-baxter-travenol.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>huang, cable, baxter travenol</b></span></a>'},{question:"does POSITA possess knowledge and skills rendering him capable of combining the prior art references.",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/04/dystar.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>dystar</b></span></a>'},{question:"objective evidence of secondary considerations operates as a beneficial check on hindsight.",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/04/leapfrog-ksr-cheese-systems-natl-steel.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>cheese systems</b></span></a>'},{question:"must show combination uniquely challenging or difficult for POSITA",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/04/leapfrog-ksr-cheese-systems-natl-steel.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>leapfrog, ksr</b></span></a>'},{question:"that two inventions designed to resolve different problems not enough for teaching away",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/04/leapfrog-ksr-cheese-systems-natl-steel.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>natl steel, fulton</b></span></a>'},{question:"All words in a claim must be considered in judging the obviousness of the claimed subject matter.",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/04/wilson.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>wilson</b></span></a>'},{question:"analogous art must logically have commended itself to inventor's attention considering his problem",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/04/icon.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>ICON</b></span></a>'},{question:"factual findings required to apply enumerated rationales from MPEP 2143",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/04/ksr.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>KSR</b></span></a>'},{question:"have to show combination was 'uniquely challenging or difficult' for POSITA",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/05/leapfrog.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>leapfrog</b></span></a>'},{question:"analogous art (1) same field of endeavor or (2) reasonably pertinent to the particular problem",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/05/bigio-klein.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>bigio, klein</b></span></a>'},{question:"may be unobvious to omit element while retaining its function",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/06/edge.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>edge</b></span></a>'},{question:"simultaneous advantages and disadvantages doesnt obviate motivation to combine",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/06/winner-intl-medichem.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>winner int'l, medichem</b></span></a>'},{question:"reasonable expectation that references could be combined successfully is necessary part of a prima facie case",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/06/vaeck.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>vaeck</b></span></a>'},{question:"saying a prior art could perform as claimed without saying why obvious to modify isnt prima facie case",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/06/giannelli.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>giannelli</b></span></a>'},{question:"existence of an apparatus does not render unpatentable all the possible methods to which it may be adapted",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/06/carnegie.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>carnegie</b></span></a>'},{question:"invention may be novel as to prior art without teaching away from combining prior art with invention",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/06/ricoh.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>ricoh</b></span></a>'},{question:"Whether a reference teaches away from a claimed invention is a question of fact.",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/06/harris.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>harris</b></span></a>'},{question:"technological incompatibility relevant for arguing against combination, not economic reasons",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/06/farrenkopf-orthopedic.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>farrenkopf, orthopedic</b></span></a>'},{question:"discovery of optimum range only obvious when general conditions of claim disclosed in prior art",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/06/aller-kahn.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>aller, kahn</b></span></a>'},{question:"103 prima facie can be rebutted if can show that the art in any material respect taught away",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/07/geisler-gurley.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>geisler, gurley</b></span></a>'},{question:"to teach away ref would lead POSITA in a direction divergent from the path that was taken by the applicant",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/07/ricoh.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>ricoh</b></span></a>'},{question:"deficiency in factual basis for legal conclusion of obviousness resolved in favor of applicant",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/07/alice-warner.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>warner</b></span></a>'},{question:"single conveyor not enough when claim requires two conveyors",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/07/lantech-robertson.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>lantech</b></span></a>'},{question:"ranges approaching each other enough of a reason to reject where end points approximate",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/07/ksr-patel.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>KSR, patel</b></span></a>'},{question:"preponderance of the evidence must show nonpatentability",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/07/porter-caveney.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>caveney</b></span></a>'},{question:"prima facie burden not met when rejection so uninformative cant recognize grounds",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/07/therasence-schering-continental-can.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>chester</b></span></a>'},{question:"'obvious to try' does not apply if combination has longer-lasting efficacy than either alone",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/08/sanofi-aventis-pozen.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>sanofi-aventis, pozen</b></span></a>'},{question:"103 rejections need articulated reasoning with rational underpinning",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/08/kahn.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>kahn</b></span></a>'},{question:"secondary considerations are a beneficial check on hindsight",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/08/kerkhoven-cheese-systems.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>cheese systems</b></span></a>'},{question:"combining two compositions to form third used for same purpose obvious",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/08/kerkhoven-cheese-systems.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>kerkhoven</b></span></a>'},{question:"even if prior art genus huge, if discloses species, used for same purpose as applicant, then obvious",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/08/merck-susi.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>merck, susi</b></span></a>'},{question:"103 in chemical arts: is it a lead compound?, reasonable expectation of success to modify it",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/08/otsuka-takeda-altana.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>otsuka, takeda, altana</b></span></a>'},{question:"knowledge of the goal does not render its achievement obvious",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/08/institut-pasteur.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>institut pasteur</b></span></a>'},{question:"no req. only successful product for commercial success",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/08/phillips-bristol-myers-continental-can.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>bristol-myers, continental can, kansas jack, goodyear dental</b></span></a>'},{question:"The test for obviousness is not whether secondary reference may be incorporated into primary reference",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/08/keller-datamize-musgrave-nystrom.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>keller</b></span></a>'},{question:"103 affirmed when no indication obtaining claimed dimensions beyond POSITA capabilities",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/08/applied-materials-aller-cybersettle.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #e69138;"><b>applied materials, aller</b></span></a>'},{question:"adequate traverse must create reasonable doubt regarding notice of what is well known to POSITA",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/08/boon.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>boon</b></span></a>'},{question:"no per se rule of obviousness",answer:'<a href="http://www.ptab.us/2014/08/custom-search-reversed-tech-center-1700.html" style="color: #3366ff;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><b>MPEP § 2144</b></span></a>'}
     ];
